<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Kunza Rizvi, Author at Nomisma digital</title>
	<atom:link href="/author/kunzarizvi/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>World&#039;s best marketplace for complex financial services</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Why we are closing our doors for pre-revenue Startups &#8211; Faisal Khan</title>
		<link>/2021/04/20/why-we-are-closing-our-doors-for-pre-revenue-startups-faisal-khan/</link>
					<comments>/2021/04/20/why-we-are-closing-our-doors-for-pre-revenue-startups-faisal-khan/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kunza Rizvi]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/04/20/why-we-are-closing-our-doors-for-pre-revenue-startups-faisal-khan/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>For years, we have been advocates of sharing information and educating everyone for the greater benefit and good of society. This includes individuals, startups, would-be-entrepreneurs, incumbents, colleagues, professionals in the field, etc. However, this open-door policy has started to take its toll on our resources &#8211; specifically human resources &#8211; and the available time we &#8230;</p>
<p class="read-more"> <a class="" href="/2021/04/20/why-we-are-closing-our-doors-for-pre-revenue-startups-faisal-khan/"> <span class="screen-reader-text">Why we are closing our doors for pre-revenue Startups &#8211; Faisal Khan</span> Read More &#187;</a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/04/20/why-we-are-closing-our-doors-for-pre-revenue-startups-faisal-khan/">Why we are closing our doors for pre-revenue Startups &#8211; Faisal Khan</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Nomisma digital</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For years, we have been advocates of sharing information and educating everyone for the greater benefit and good of society. This includes individuals, startups, would-be-entrepreneurs, incumbents, colleagues, professionals in the field, etc.</p>
<p>However, this open-door policy has started to take its toll on our resources &ndash; specifically human resources &ndash; and the available time we have.</p>
<p>It is with regret that we now inform our patrons, that we will not be onboarding any new pre-revenue clients (or startups that are pre-revenue).</p>
<p>Allow us to explain our reasons.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Every single day, we get between 5 -10 relevant leads &ndash; on many days, the numbers are much higher. A vast majority of them start with &ldquo;I would like to start a X-Business&rdquo; where x=money transfer, neo bank, cross border payments, crypto, blockchain, bitcoin trading, e-wallet, EMI, PSP, merchant processor, etc.</p>
<p>The sad truth is that most of these inquiries will never become functioning businesses mostly due to financing (or the lack thereof).</p>
<p>Most of these inquiries involve asking a myriad of questions, trying to get educated, and validating their various business ideas for free. While we have always welcomed enthusiastic new entrants to come and &ldquo;pick my brain&rdquo;, it is becoming increasingly difficult to entertain them all.&nbsp;</p>
<p>Having done over 7,500+ calls, we&rsquo;ve noticed the following patterns (not all may be applicable to you).</p>
<ul>
<li>Unwillingness to spend 50, 100, 200 or so hours in learning about their business vertical even though they have never done the business before</li>
<li>Almost everyone seems to have &ldquo;a big idea&rdquo; for becoming the next neo-bank, the next large money transfer company, the next big bitcoin exchange, yet, they struggle to even read 5 pages of condensed material</li>
<li>Their &ldquo;business&rdquo; is still in the brainstorming/ideas stage and they have no idea how to proceed with any of the pre-requisites but are still unwilling to read or learn about it</li>
<li>Basic company formation is not even started and licenses are yet to be applied for</li>
<li>Most of these entrepreneurs/startups, don&rsquo;t read the resources we have provided or watch the instructional videos, even when prompted to do so</li>
<li>Their collective research on the subject/industry is very limited</li>
<li>Spending time in reading and understanding written material is frowned upon</li>
<li>Most will argue and try to bend official rules (because they have a limited understanding of the laws and regulations)</li>
<li>Far too many people fudge the information on their application forms</li>
<li>Very, very few people can actually make a financial model for their proposed big idea</li>
<li>Even fewer people can make a legally compliant flow of funds</li>
<li>Almost no one has undertaken even the very basic anti-money laundering training &ndash; we have been in countless completely fruitless conversations trying to explain what needs to be done, etc.</li>
</ul>
<p>However, the most important three points:</p>
<ul>
<li>It is a thankless job</li>
<li>No appreciation for our time</li>
<li>Not having the courtesy to reply back to emails, once information was gained from us</li>
</ul>
<p>With that in view, we have decided not to offer our services or schedule calls with pre-revenue entrepreneurs/startups.</p>
<p>We are sure many of you would find this distasteful, but we would urge you to understand that we are taking this step after a lot of deliberation and hard discussions. It feels unfair to our paying clients if we continue to waste time with non-serious leads who have no intention of moving forward with us. We believe it makes more sense &ndash; for our business and our mental health &ndash;&nbsp; to prioritize those who appreciate the assistance we provide and who have a strong probability of becoming a paying client.</p>
<p>However, we are not shutting the door on you. If you believe you are a startup, even pre-revenue, but can demonstrate your understanding of the business and proof of funds, please <a href='https://faisalkhan.com/contact'>contact us</a> so that we may discuss further.</p>
<p>&mdash;</p>
<p>This page was last updated on April 20, 2021.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2021/04/20/why-we-are-closing-our-doors-for-pre-revenue-startups-faisal-khan/">Why we are closing our doors for pre-revenue Startups &#8211; Faisal Khan</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Nomisma digital</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2021/04/20/why-we-are-closing-our-doors-for-pre-revenue-startups-faisal-khan/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
